In our last tale
Di kisah sebelumnya,
Rex Lapis was walking alone in the mountains
Rex Lapis menelusuri gunung-gunung sendirian
He heard a remote voice unlike any other
Dia mendengar suara asing yang aneh
Coming from a crack in the earth
keluar dari celah bumi
Most of the ancient Geo life forms that live below Liyue are blind
Hampir semua makhluk Geo kuno yang hidup di bawah Liyue tidak memiliki penglihatan
Having not seen the sunlight for an age
Entah berapa lama tidak melihat sinar matahari
The voice was sometimes sad and songlike, other times it was loud and thunderous
Suaranya terkadang sedih seperti nyanyian, terkadang keras menggelegar
The Lord of Geo searched here and there
Lord of Geo mencari kesana kemari
Before finally unearthing a strange stone from the bedrock
Sebelum akhirnya menemukan sebuah batu aneh dari formasi bebatuan
That's how Azhdaha was
Itulah Azhdaha
I answered his wish, and took him above ground
Aku menjawab panggilannya, dan mengangkatnya keluar dari bawah tanah
The Lord of Geo took pity on the rock's spirit
Lord of Geo mengasihani roh batu tersebut
And carved it into a magnificent work of craftsmanship — a vivid representation of a dragon
Dan mengukirnya menjadi maha karya yang luar biasa — menjadi wujud seekor naga yang hidup
I bestowed him with a pair of eyes to see the world
Aku memberikan sepasang mata padanya, agar dia dapat melihat dunia
And came to an agreement with him
Dan membuat kesepakatan dengannya
With his fingers, he made two eyes
Dengan jarinya, dia membuat dua mata
Quicker than words could tell, lightning flashed and thunder roared
Dalam sekejap, kilat menyambar dan guntur menggelegar
And a living, breathing dragon soared into the clouds!
seekor naga yang hidup terbang menembus awan!
I agreed to let him live among the people above ground
Aku membiarkannya hidup dengan orang-orang di atas tanah
But if the day ever came when he brought ruin to order
Tapi jika suatu hari dia menyebabkan kekacauan
He would once again be sealed in the dark
Dia akan disegel kembali dalam kegelapan
The dragon accompanied the Lord of Geo
Naga tersebut lalu menemani Lord of Geo
Fighting campaigns alongside him in the four corners of the world
Menyertainya berperang di empat penjuru dunia
We have a saying to eulogize these events:
Sebuah pepatah pun lahir dari kisah ini,
"The crash of a spear brought billowing dust"
"Tombak emas menghantam bumi dan tanah menjadi debu,
"The mountains and waters made way at the sound"
dari mata tombak itu gunung-gunung dan perairan terbelah"
"The sight of a dragon bestowed with a touch"
"Naga dengan anugerah penglihatan akan sebuah wahyu,
"The promise of rainwater blessing the ground"
mendatangkan berkat dalam hujannya yang turun ke tanah"